Contact

eskarbinski@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/beth-skarbinski-0170a471 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Management Risk Assessment

Certifications

CPHRM

Perinatal Bereavement Counselor Alternative Dispute Resolution

Beth Skarbinski

CNO

Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

Summary

I have 32 years experience as a Registered Nurse (22 years in obsterics and neonatology, 20 years in nursing administration) and 11 years in risk management. I am a skilled presenter and communicator, expert witness, mediator, and perinatal bereavement counselor. I am currently certified as a risk manager (CPHRM) as well as in patient safety (CPPS).

Experience

Central Carolina Hospital
Chief Nursing Officer
September 2019 - Present (11 months)

Southern New Hampshire University Adjunct Faculty January 2017 - Present (3 years 7 months)

Duke University Medical Center
Director of Clinical Risk Management
February 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Director of clinical risk for Duke Hospital with 6 direct reports. Manage day to day risk concerns within the hospital, management of actual and potential claims, and network with leaders across the facility to reduce overall exposure. I track and trend risk concerns and assist with the development of plans to improve outcomes.

Central Maine Healthcare 8 years 9 months

System Director of Risk and Claims Management September 2009 - February 2015 (5 years 6 months) Lewiston/Auburn, Maine Area

claims manager for a self insured hospital system. Additionally I managed adverse event reporting (tracking and trending), built risk dashboards,

performed risk assessments, coordinated root cause analysis and FMEAs as well as developed processes to reduce overall hospital risks and exposure.

Nurse Manager

June 2006 - September 2009 (3 years 4 months)

Lewiston/Auburn, Maine Area

Birthing center leader

Maine Medical Center Staff RN

September 2004 - June 2006 (1 year 10 months)

Portland, Maine Area

Labor and delivery

Sturdy Memorial Hospital

10 years 5 months

Nurse Manager

September 2001 - December 2004 (3 years 4 months)

Maternal Child Health Clinical Educator

August 1994 - September 2001 (7 years 2 months)

Director of clinical risk management including risk mitigation and claims management. Identification of trends, adverse event evaluation, networking with healthcare team members and development of process improvement.

Education

Creighton University School of Medicine

Masters in Healthcare Ethics, Medicine · (2013 - 2014)

Salve Regiona University

Bacholors of Science, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1984 - 1986)

Laboure College

Associate of Science (A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (1982 - 1984)